Cao Trần Trọng Nghĩa

PRODUCT MANAGER | PRODUCT OWNER | BA & UI UX DESIGNER



Male

🛗 June 20, 1989

د

_

♥ Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

SKILLS

Language

English (Advanced), Vietnamese (Native)

Others

Product Management, Business Analyst, UI UX Design, Team Leadership, Teamwork, User Experience (UX), Analytical Skills, Time Management

HONORS & AWARDS

Nov 2021: Top 20/350 TechFest, Vietnam National Innovation Startup Competition

Nov 2013: Top 1st graduated ranking, score: 3.6/4

OBJECTIVE

I love to build product which can be engaged & highly adopted by customers. Experienced to manage product team to understand, define, ideate, prototype, development and ship better experiences for a variety of web/mobile applications, and platforms with agile and lean development models.

WORK EXPERIENCE

HMT Corporation

CX PRODUCT MANAGER

Nov 2020 - Present

Manage product team to build web/mobile product with user centered approach to solve customer paint points, my key responsibilities include:

- Conduct market research and always keep finding opportunities to grow/shape product.
- Create user persona, Provide UX with user-centered approach
- Align with senior management team and marketing team with product development strategy
- Turning the product vision into an actionable backlog & manage team to achieve deliverable goals
- Analyzed metrics data to improve product usability or come up with new demand features.
- Present product to recruit early adopter & target investors

WEBSITES

ACHIEVEMENT

One of products was selected to TOP 20 among 350 teams participated in TechFest 2021 - Vietnam National Innovation Startup Competition

LeadVision

UI UX DESIGNER | BUSINESS ANALYST | PRODUCT OWNER

Dec 2014 - Nov 2020

Joined at early stage of LeadVision at Vietnam, I had an experience to setup development center at Vietnam and it was the first time I had a chance to setup workspace, formed up a development team & started building digital platform from scratch.

Based on CEO's vision, I managed & developed digital transformation platform consists of ERP, Process & Performance Management, and especially Strategy & Portfolio Management products to bring the digital transparency value, live assessment & predictive analysis to client's management team.

ACHIEVEMENT: 4 solutions had been successfully granted patent by IP Australia

DXC Technology

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2013 - Dec 2014

After passing fresher training program, my career started at DXC with role SharePoint Software Engineer.

By having a good training results & graduation, I was chosen to join to development team for Zurich Insurance Group, one of the most valuable England customers for DXC at that time.

During approx. 2 years, I was mainly responsible for developing features assigned from Product Manager / Technical Lead for internal CMS products. I learned a lot of skills here from technical, communication to standard development process when working with giant enterprise customers.

My utilization was always over 95%, a very satisfactory performance level by DXC. This achievement gave me a lot of chances to join other potential projects, promoted by managers & mentor.

Freelancer

WEB DEVELOPER

Sep 2011 - Dec 2014

Being a freelancer to build landing pages for various clients from Vietnam & Australia during university period.

EDUCATION

Hoa sen university

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Information Technology

GPA: 3.6/4, top 1st graduated

Hoa sen university

Associate of Science (A.S.), Information Technology